simplyhappyfoodie.com 2019-04-08

# Privacy Policy | Simply Happy Foodie

## PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTE ON TERMS OF USE

Simply Happy Foodie found at https://www.simplyhappyfoodie.com/ (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”). We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

## WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?

Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website: We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

Information We Collect from Others: We may receive information about you from other sources. You may choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts on the Website. If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts anywhere on the Website, we will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

Automatically-Collected Information: We may automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we may log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

MY LATEST VIDEOS

Cookies: When you use the Website, we may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

In addition, third-party service providers with whom we have contracted may collect certain of your personal information when you access the Website. See Third Party Use of Personal Information, below.

## HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

We may use the information collected in the following ways:  
To operate and maintain the Website;  
To send you promotional information, such as newsletters only if you opt-in to email notifications. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;  
To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;  
To respond to your comments, inquiries and requests;  
To track and measure advertising on the Website;  
To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity;  
To assist in our maintenance of up-to-date records; and  
To carry out privacy impact assessments.

## THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics advises us that it may capture your IP address, but that no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.  
Please refer to Google Analytics’ privacy policy, found [HERE](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), for more information.

Mail Chimp – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. Mail Chimp stores your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Please refer to Mail Chimp’s privacy policy, found [HERE](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/), for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be changed from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion. We will notify you by email of any such changes.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

## ANONYMOUS DATA

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

## PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION

If you leave a comment on our Website, certain information may be publicly visible. Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

## COOKIES

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent and permanently deny the setting of cookies by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time through settings in your Internet browser or through the use of other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

If you would like to find out more about cookies please visit this website: [https://www.aboutcookies.com](https://www.aboutcookies.com/)

### Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

 **For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com and contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

### ADVERTISING

Display Ads  
We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

Retargeting Ads  
From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

Affiliate Program Participation  
The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

The Website is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Currently, the Website does not participate in affiliate advertising program with any vendor other than the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program. If this were to change, we would notify you of this fact by email.

Amazon Services LLC advises that it does not collect personal information in connection with its Associates Program affiliated advertising service.

## Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns.

Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user.

The results of individual users’ tracking pixels will not be shared with third parties by the Website, although anonymous analytics derived from tracking pixels may be shared with third parties for purposes of evaluating the efficacy of our email campaigns.

## RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com to be removed from our mailing list.  
Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com.  
Amend – You may contact us at sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com to amend or update your personal information.  
Forget – You may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com.  
Restricted Processing–You may request that we cease or limit processing your personal information. To do so, please submit a request to sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com.  
Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

## SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

At no time will the Website request, nor should you submit to the Website, sensitive personal information, such as your social security or other governmental identification number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships.

## CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com and we will promptly remove such information from our records.

## REVISIONS TO PRIVACY POLICY

The terms of this Privacy Policy may be revised, amended or supplemented from time to time. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email of the changes we have made or intend to make.

## CONTACT INFORMATION

At any time, please contact us at sandy@simplyhappyfoodie.com for questions and requests related to this Privacy Policy and the information we collect.  
Last updated: Sept. 18, 2018.
